

Jerick Ramos Eva

Lead Consultant at HCL technologies Philippines

Contact Details:

(+63) 9672769527 evajerick21@gmail.com

PEGA Version used: Certifications:

PEGA version 8.6 PEGA version 8.3 PEGA version 8.1 PEGA version 7.4 PEGA Version 7.2

Certified PEGA Senior System Architect Version 7.2

Certified PEGA System Architect Version 7.1

Work Summary:

I have been working using PEGA from late 2014 until present. I

have worked in the following countries:

Philippines (2014 to 2018) - Claims and Insurance (Australia

and Asia)

Singapore (2018 to 2021) - Banking & Finance, and

Government of Singapore (MOM)

Philippines (2021 to present) – Banking(ING)

Skills:

- PEGA Proficient
- Pega Client Lifecycle Management for Financial Services
- Pega Survey Framework
- Designing structure and implementation of integration using services and connector like REST or SOAP.
- React JS
- Reporting and technical rules.
- PEGA System administrators and User interface
- Type and Case Management/Workflow.
- Object Oriented Design and Programming.
- PEGA Implementation Architecture expertise.

- Setup the Pega class structure and application rule set structure for an enterprise.
- PEGA Agents, Queue Processing and SLA.
- Used various techniques including Pega's PAL to identify and fix Pega application performance bottlenecks.
- Experienced in using application log, Tracer, clipboard to identify Pega application problems.
- Data migration. BAU/Production Support.
- XML, JSON, WSDL web messages format.
- Agile development and scrum process.
- HTML/CSS
- Understand and can work independently using SQL (mySQL, SQL, DB2, ORACLE)
- SOAPUI/SOA For testing services and connectors
- Have been working on different phases of environment
- On hands experience on Survey Framework(Specific pega product)
- Understand and able to use custom HTML/CSS javascript in PEGA application if necessary.

Work Experience:

Lead Consultant at ING Philippines (2022 to Present)

ING Philippines

Apr 2022 - Present

Manila, National Capital Region, Philippines.

Under DEVOps for FEC Policy Squad Manila (GKYC Policy Cluster).

Roles:

DevOps Under for FEC Policy Squad Manila (GKYC Policy Cluster) Roles Development and Automation of unit testing

Skills: Pega Developer

Lead Consultant at HCL technologies Philippines (2021 to Present)

Nov 2021 - Present

Metro Manila, National Capital Region, Philippines

Specialized in Pega Platform development.

Current Project involvement:

04/2022

Project: ING - Global GKYC under FECNP (FEC (Financial Economic Crime) processes for Natural Persons).

Role: Development/ Operations (Automation Unit Testing in PEGA) Specialized in Pega Platform development.

Current Project involvement: 04/2022 Project: ING - Global GKYC under FECNP (FEC (Financial

Economic Crime) processes for Natural Persons).

Role: Development/ Operations (Automation Unit Testing in PEGA)

Skills: Software Development using PEGA

Software Developer using PEGA - Avenys Agency (Deployed to the Ministry of Manpower in Singapore)

Started from September 2020 to Current Project worked on:

Labour Statistics Survey Portal(LSSP) - Application for Singaporean that allows them to answer the survey and provide details of each family member and allow them to answer surveys in behalf of them. Surveys are updated every 6 months and data captured will be sync from Internet to Intranet and v/v.

Role: Modified Skin, Harness or mostly UI, specially updating the templates of the survey based on the business requirements. It also includes modifying HTML/CSS adding jquery/javascript and updating Web-login. And make sure the application runs on all devices.

Application Developer (PEGA) - Luxoft Company (Singapore) Started from June 2019 to July 2020

Projects worked on:

MORE STP – Application for building business in Singapore. I worked on back-end development using PEGA Services (Service-REST) and (Connect-REST). I am also responsible for the design and REF generation of the application, and work on this project

from DEV to PROD.

ALS – it is an auto loan application online that reduces the manual process. I worked on the UI part of PEGA and (Connect-REST). Also collaborate with business users for requirements gathering for change requests.

CIU - it is a pure PEGA application, and I worked mostly on UI, and services mapping of request and response of the services (Integration).

OBAO – it is an online application also, with Angular as front-end and PEGA as back-end software. I worked on request and response mapping from UI and vice versa, Services (REST) and Connect (REST).

Structured Deposit Application (Changed Request) – I worked on 3 changed requests on this project which also involve mapping of request and response from the services. End-to end testing, deployment, and support as BAU.

ITSR – I worked on lists of changes requests for OCBC applications that include PEGA changes in the back-end.

Application Developer (PEGA) - Compo 2000 Pte Ltd (Singapore) Started from April 2018 to June 2019

Projects worked on:

Structured Deposit Application – it involves integration with a lot of services, from UI and from third party applications. I also worked here from DEV to PROD and BAU support, and was responsible for the mapping of requests and responses from the service. We implement Service (SOAP) and Connect (SOAP) on this project.

Structured Deposit Cancellation – it is a continuation of the project above (SDA) but this is to cancel the product that was applied in a structured deposit application. I am responsible for the development of the whole project from DEV to PROD because it is only a pure PEGA application with integration of service (Connect-SOAP).

ITSR – I worked on 2 changes requests for an OCBC application that includes PEGA changes in the back-end.

Senior System Analyst (PEGA) - Accenture Philippines (Quezon City, Philippines) Started from November 2017 to March 2018

Project worked on:

MUFG – it is a banking and finance application that I have worked on. My responsibilities here are UI design and support. I also worked on

mapping of data from external applications and creating modules for the application.

Application Developer (PEGA) - DXC Philippines (Makati City, Philippines) Started from October 2014 to September 2017

This is my first working experience as an application developer using PEGA.

Our project was also insurance, which is QBE that is also available in different countries like HK, SG, MY and Australia. I have been part of project development and support.

Project worked on:

QBE Insurance – I worked on UI, generating reports, data mapping, deployments, support (BAU) and enhancements

- Involves in Gatekeeping (Secures, creates, and promotes ruleset in DEV to PROD environment).
- Make decisions and score performance against the business plan and individual business objectives.

Creates Technical Business Requirements Documents

Education:

Batangas State University - Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (Batangas, Philippines)

Our focus is on programming with different programming languages, processes, algorithms, SDLC and computing sciences.

Character References:

Project Manager: Sonny Torres (+65) 92303513

General Manager: Murthy Rallabandi (+65) 90495812

I do hereby declare that all the information given above is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.